{
    "id": "84ada1f1fc764c79b48c4d76e7ac9473",
    "title": "Identification of adverbs worksheet",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "0014debb8f364534aa7840fc392a35e6",
            "title": "Identify the adverb",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "There is clearly something wrong with her.",
                    "description": "Adverbs are words that indicate ideas such as time, place, manner and frequency. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "clearly",
                        "wrong",
                        "with"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is my teacher but she is also my friend.",
                    "description": "But is a conjunction and friend is a noun. Also is the adverb. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "but",
                        "friend",
                        "also"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He always wears a coat, even in summer.",
                    "description": "Wears is a verb and summer is a noun. Always is the adverb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "always",
                        "wears",
                        "summer"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He often comes and stays with us.",
                    "description": "With is a preposition and is a conjunction often is an adverb of frequency",
                    "answers": [
                        "with",
                        "often",
                        "and"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am going to Venice today.",
                    "description": "Time words are adverbs.",
                    "answers": [
                        "am",
                        "to",
                        "today"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You have definitely been a great help.",
                    "description": "Words ending in -ly are usually adverbs note that there are a few exceptions to this rule. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "definitely",
                        "been",
                        "great"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "This time next week, I will be happily working in my garden.",
                    "description": "Next is an adjective garden is a noun happily is the adverb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "next",
                        "happily",
                        "garden"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I donâ€™t think the repair has been properly done.",
                    "description": "Properly is an adverb indicating manner.",
                    "answers": [
                        "think",
                        "repair",
                        "properly"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am really sorry for disturbing you.",
                    "description": "Really is an adverb indicating manner.",
                    "answers": [
                        "really",
                        "sorry",
                        "disturbing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We went to bed early.",
                    "description": "Words indicating time, place, manner, frequency, condition etc., are all adverbs. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "early",
                        "went",
                        "to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The war seriously affected oil prices.",
                    "description": "Words indicating manner are adverbs.",
                    "answers": [
                        "war",
                        "seriously",
                        "affected"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She must sometimes have wanted to run away.",
                    "description": "Words indicating time and frequency are adverbs.",
                    "answers": [
                        "must",
                        "sometimes",
                        "run"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}